

Md Murad Raihan 1230, Uttara Sector-10 Dhaka Contact: +8801533694189

Mail:<u>Here</u> Portfolio



OBJECTIVES

[A highly motivated a Result-oriented fresh graduate proficient in programming languages, problem-solving, and software development, seeking a position in a growth-oriented company to leverage skills and creativity for mutual benefit. Eager to contribute to innovative organisational works while enhancing personal growth and skills within a dynamic team environment.]

SKILLS & EXPERTISE

Language: C,C++,C#, JAVA(JavaFX) Python (Django), Javascript (React-Js ReactNative), Dart & OOP Concept. Git, GitHub.

Frontend Development: HTML, CSS, TainwindCSS, Bootstrap, Javascript & React JS

Backend Development:Python,Django **App Development Basic:** React Native

All My Works In My Portfolio: Here

GitHub: (7) LinkedIn: in

BASIC COMPUTER SKILLS

- MS Word
- MS Excel
- PowerPoint
- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe Illustrator
- Logo Design
- Banner Design

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Computer Science and Engineering 2020-2024 International University of Business Agriculture and Technology (IUBAT)- Department of CSE **Result** – 3.20 out of 4.00

Higher Secondary Certificate, HSC 2019 Dr. Mahbubur Rhaman Molla College – Jatrabari, Dhaka Group – Science GPA-4.50

Secondary School Certificate, SSC 2017 Mannan High School & College – Jatrabari, Dhaka Group – Science GPA-4.91

SOFTWARE PROJECTS & THESIS

Bus Ticket Management System: Developed a Java-based Bus Ticket Management System facilitating efficient ticket Booking and money transaction management. **Utilized:** Java, JavaFX & MySQL.

E-Commerce Website: Constructed an Interactive e-commerce Website using Python (Django) that offers seamless product browsing, shopping cart functionality, and Source transactions. **Utilized:** Python (Django), HTML, CSS, Bootstrap & MySQL GitHub

ICFL- IUBAT CSE Football League: Football League and Live Streaming Management System using Python (Django) that offers Buy the Team, Live streaming, Point-table, and transactions. Utilized: Python (Django), HTML, CSS, Bootstrap & MySQL.

Small Organization Taekown-do Website: Developed a React-js based Taekwondo frontend web template facilitating efficient informative, package Booking and student attendance management. Utilized: React JS, CSS, Bootstrap, Google-font. -Follow GitHub

Thesis: Deep Learning-Based Driver Drowsiness Detection Model with an Alarming System.

I worked with innovative methodologies to facilitate Driver Drowsiness Detection by the OpenCV and TensorFlow Alarming system Computer Vision and Machine Learning Processed with integrated by the algorithms.

Utilized: Python, OpenCV & (Tensor-Flow, Kears, dlib,)

Algorithm: Haar cascade, CNN

EXPERIENCE

- ■Pioneer Alpha| Software Development Intern 26-May 2024 – 20-Aug-2024
- •IUBAT IT Society | January 2023 April 2023 Academic Mentor Key responsibilities: Provide academic

guidance and support to students.

ABOUT ME

I am a hardworking individual who has a passion for learning technologies. To find a challenging position to meet my competencies, capabilities, skills, education & experience. I want to engage myself in an organization where there is an opportunity to contribute to the growth of the organization as well as personal skills.

CERTIFICATES & AWARDS

- English Book Reading Competition Award from IELTS Bangladesh
- jubo unnayan proshikkhon computer certificate
- Jagroto Bibek -JB organization, Best Social Volunteer Awards.

LANGUAGE

Bangla, English.

INTERESTS

Programming, Learning New Technologies, Write Poem & Traveling

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Name : Murad Raihan Date of Birth : 01-02-2001

Permanent Address : Jatrabari, Demra Dhaka-1362

Present Address : 1230, Uttara, sector-10, R-12b, H-14,

Nationality : Bangladeshi

REFERENCE

MS. Moumitu Tasnim

Senior Lecturer (IUBAT)

Department of CSE

Room No: 1015 E-mail: moumitu.cse@iubat.edu

Phone: +88-01841958584

Suhala Lamia

Assistant Professor (IUBAT)

Department of CSE Room No: 1014

E-mail: <u>suhalalamia@iubat.edu</u> Phone: +880 1931235286

Krishna Das

Assistant Professor (IUBAT)

Department of CSE Room No: 514,

E-mail: krishna.das@iubat.edu Phone: +880 15 5354 3733